<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book xml:id="Overview"
	version="5.0"
	xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:inkscape="http://www.inkscape.org/namespaces/inkscape"
	xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<article xml:id="Overview-Main">
		<title>Overview</title>
		<section>
			<title>Field of Application &amp; USPs</title>
			<section>
				<title>Business Application Challenges</title>
				<para>Programming complex business applications in a regular programming language
					such as Java has a few challenges regarding process execution:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>State Management</emphasis></para>
						<para>When your program needs to wait on a particular event (e. g. a user
							entering some data, some external system responding to a request or some
							computation to be completed), it will block memory and CPU resources
							while waiting. Also, when somebody turns off the computer or the program
							crashes, the state of the program will get lost resulting in an
							uncompleted process.</para>
						<para>In order to get this problem resolved, you need to use a persistence
							mechanism (i. e. a database) to save the state of your program to and
							you need to implement the logic that suspends and resumes your program
							upon completion of the pending task. Usually, this complex logic becomes
							rather application-specific, requiring additional maintenance and
							extensive testing effort.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Business Functionality Definition</emphasis></para>
						<para>Java being an architecture-orientated language does not provide
							functionality that is really suitable for business specialists to
							describe business functionality. The business functionality (i. e. what
							- from a business point of view - needs to be done with the objects that
							are managed or processed by the program) often gets lost somewhere
							between frameworks, architecture patterns and technical configuration.
							Sometimes even smaller functional changes (e. g. adding an additional
							workflow step such as a confirmation by a manager) can proof a complex
							task.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="linktest1">
				<title>Business Process, Workflow &amp; Co.</title>
				<para>According to different requirements, processes within software applications
					can be grouped in three categories:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Business Processes</emphasis></para>
						<para>A business process is a rather high-level process that defines how
							distributed systems interact in a heterogeneous environment. Business
							processes can span across companies, systems and programming platforms
							and languages. The focus of business process management is on enterprise
							application integration and safety. Business process engines need to
							integrate with middleware software and need to follow cross-platform
							standards.</para>
						<para>An example of a business process may be an order process that involves
							an ERP system, a CRM system and various external partners providing
							fulfillment and delivery services in a SOA environment.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Workflow Process</emphasis></para>
						<para>A workflow process defines the interaction of the different roles
							within an organization in order to perform a business task. Though roles
							can be fulfilled by persons as well as systems, workflows have an
							organizational rather than a technical focus.</para>
						<para>A typical workflow may determine how a vacation application needs to
							be processed when running through a department.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Application Process</emphasis></para>
						<para>An application process is a process that defines how a particular
							business functionality within an application is to be performed.</para>
						<para>An example might be the steps that need to be performed by a
							production machine in order to manufacture an item.</para>
						<para>Though also in this type of process interaction with external systems
							or roles may be required, the focus is on the business functionality
							within the application, requiring an emphasis on performance and
							integration with the Java environment.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para><emphasis>Process engines</emphasis>are frameworks that take a process
					definition in some formal language (usually XML-based) and execute it step by on
					a set of data (the process context). The process definition is either written
					manually or in some cases generated by a graphical process modeling tool.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>What is OpenBP?</title>
				<para>OpenBP is an open Java-based process and workflow platform. The platform
					consists of a sophisticated graphical process modelling tool (the modeler) and a
					process execution framework (the engine). The engine executes the XML-based
					business process definitions that are created and edited in the modeller.</para>
				<para>The OpenBP modeler allows the developer or business process specialist to
					visually model business processes and workflows as flowchart or UML activity
					diagrams using simple drag &amp; drop. The OpenBP Modeler is intended to be used
					by software developers as well as process specialists and consultants.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>What's Different To Other Process Engines?</title>
				<para>OpenBP provides the following USPs as compared to other process
					engines:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Lightweight application processes</emphasis></para>
						<para>OpenBP is focused on application processes. Its goal is to bring
							pragmatic and performant process support to any type of application, be
							it administrative, technical or even real-time.</para>
						<para>Pragmatic, fast and flexible approach for application processes</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Sophisticated graphical process modeling</emphasis></para>
						<para>A sophisticated modeling tool enables comfortable process design,
							supporting all features of the modeling language. There is <emphasis>no
								need for manual editing of the process XML.</emphasis></para>
						<para>Excellent tool support for business specialists as well as
							developers.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Extremely fast suspend &amp; resume</emphasis></para>
						<para>As opposed to some other process engines that have a pretty complex
							database footprint, OpenBP processes can be suspended to the database or
							resumed extremely fast. In addition, the interaction of OpenBP with the
							database is always transparent. There is no indeterminable 'magic'
							behind the scenes.</para>
						<para>Support for high-performance process execution</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Process debugger</emphasis></para>
						<para>In OpenBP, the execution of a process can be traced in the graphical
							modeling environment. Process debugging does not require debugging of
							the process engine on the Java level. Even the process context data can
							be viewed in the modeling tool, making process development a snap. In
							some deployment scenarios, process definitions can be updated in the
							modeling tool without even having to restart the running
							application.</para>
						<para>Process-level debugging aids developer productivity
							considerably</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Hot Deployment</emphasis></para>
						<para>OpenBP supports hot deployment, which eliminates the 'Build' and
							'Deploy' step in your Development - Build - Deploy - Test cycle for the
							logic realized as OpenBP process. Any change in a process can be
							reflected instantaneous to the server that runs the OpenBP engine - in
							most cases even while debugging the process.</para>
						<para>Hot deployment saves a lot of time by eliminating the 'Build' and
							'Deploy' steps for process logic</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Layered Modeling</emphasis></para>
						<para>OpenBP supports different levels of interconnected models. For complex
							scenarios, you may start modeling an abstract business process (that may
							represent software-based elements as well as other activities) and drill
							down to the level of the technical process that will finally be executed
							by the process engine. Simply double-click a higher-level process
							element and the lower-level process will open.</para>
						<para>Layered modeling may help business and IT specialists communicate
							better</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis>Use case flexibility</emphasis></para>
						<para>OpenBP provides a flexible API that allows using the framework for
							different use cases such as regular process execution, dynamic
							construction of GUI pages, definition of object lifecycles (states and
							transitions) etc.</para>
						<para>All-purpose process engine</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>OpenBP also provides integration and workflow features as far as needed for
					application processes, but this is not the primary focus of the
					framework.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Basic Concepts</title>
			<section>
				<title>Process Modeling and Process Execution</title>
				<para>Similar to conventional software development, we differ between development
					and runtime.</para>
				<para>During development, you create a process model that defines how your business
					processes should be executed. The visual development environment, the OpenBP
					Modeler, will aid you in this process. The result is a series of XML
					descriptions defining your process model. They are stored in a model repository,
					which might be located in a file system directory, stored in a database or
					contained within a jar file of the classpath.</para>
				<para>At runtime, these XML files will be read from the repository by the process
					engine. On request, the process engine will execute the process model step by
					step.</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="ProcessLifecycle">
				<title>The Process Lifecycle</title>
				<para>TODO</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Model Concept</title>
				<para>OpenBP processes and supporting components are clustered in
						<firstterm>models</firstterm>. A model can be seen as container that holds
					objects that are semantically related.</para>
				<para>For example, an application might contain a model
						<literal>ErpExchange</literal> that hosts all processes that deal with
					interfacing with an ERP system.</para>
				<para>A model may refer other models (<firstterm>model import</firstterm>), defining
					a hierarchy of models. Similar to Java packages, this allows for structuring an
					application. It also supports specialization of a model (similar to Java
					subclassing) by overriding a component of an included model in the including
					model.</para>
				<para>Models are stored in <firstterm>model repositories</firstterm>.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Model Components</title>
				<para>
					<informaltable>
						<tgroup cols="2">
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Component</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>Process</entry>
									<entry>An OpenBP process that can be executed by the process
										engine.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Activity</entry>
									<entry>A template representing an activity node (usually
										refering to or containing a piece of code) that can be used
										within a process.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Visual</entry>
									<entry>A template representing a user interaction node that can
										be used within a process.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Data Type</entry>
									<entry>The (optional) definition of a data type that may be used
										as process data.</entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</informaltable>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Getting Started</title>
			<section>
				<title>Setting Up the OpenBP Distribution</title>
				<para>TODO</para>
				<para>TODO: Copy OpenBP-user.properties to HOME dir</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Installing the OpenBP Distribution</title>
				<para>TODO</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>The OpenBP Modeler</title>
			<section>
				<title>Starting The Modeler</title>
				<para>In order to start the modeler, choose the <literal>OpenBP Modeler</literal>
					menu item in the <literal>OpenBP</literal> program group.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Initial Modeler Configuration</title>
				<para>Select <guimenuitem>Cockpit|Options|Associations</guimenuitem> from the main
					menu.</para>
				<para>This tab page allows for specifying programs that will be used to display
					certain types of documents. We recommend specifying viewers for the following
					document types: <itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>text/plain: Generic text documents</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>text/x-source: Java source code</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>text/html: HTML documents (e. g. Javadoc)</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>application/pdf: PDF documents (e. g. manuals)</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist></para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>The Modeler Windows</title>
				<para>The modeler is divided into several windows:</para>
				<para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject role="fo">
							<imagedata fileref="Screenshots/Modeler_Windows.png" scale="70"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Workspace</emphasis> shows the process that is
								currently being editred. The modeler allows to edit multiple
								processes at once. Each process is displayed in its own tab page.
								You can switch between the tab pages by clicking on one of the tab
								titles below the workspace window.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Editor Toolbar</emphasis> provides the most
								important editor functions and allows for adjusting the zoom level
								and selection the presentation skin. Note that you may also change
								the zoom level by <keycap>CTRL+Mouse Wheel</keycap> or
									<keycap>CTRL+ALT+Mouse Movement</keycap>. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Workspace</emphasis> displays a particular portion
								of the current process.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Miniview</emphasis> window displays the entire
								process, providing an overview. The portion displayed by the
								workspace appears as light-blue rectangle.</para>
							<para>You may click into the miniview to position the workspace view or
								you may drag a rectangle in the miniview to redefine the portion to
								be displayed by the workspace.</para>
							<para> In the <guimenuitem>Cockpit|Options|Modeler</guimenuitem> dialog,
								you may choose how many processes are being displayed simultaneously
								in the miniview window. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Process Element Toolbox</emphasis> displays the
								standard components you may add to the process. Drag a component
								symbol from the component window to the workspace in order to create
								a new process node.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Component Browser</emphasis> lists all components
								add to the process. Drag a component symbol from the component
								window to the workspace in order to create a new process
								node.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Information Panel</emphasis> displays descriptive
								text about the currently selected element. For example, the
								information panel displays the display name and description of
								process elements in the workspace as well as components in the
								component browsers and also an help text for the currently selected
								field in the property browser.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Property Browser</emphasis> displays the properties
								of the currently selected element (i. e. an element in the workspace
								or a component in the component browser). The windows allows also
								for editing the component's properties.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Process Variable Browser.</emphasis> lists all
								process variables of the current process.</para>
							<para>You can create new process variables by dragging a data type of
								the System unit from the component browser to the process variable
								browser. Double-click an entry in order to view or edit its
								properties.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Debugger Context Inspector</emphasis> shows the
								current data context of a running process. Double-click an entry of
								the list to view any subordinate entries. Note that the inspector
								does not support changing the values of a running process.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Debugger Stack Trace Window</emphasis> shows the
								'Stack Trace' of a process that has been called as sub
								process.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The <emphasis>Color Palette</emphasis> allows assigning custom
								colors to several process elements such as activity nodes or sub
								process nodes.</para>
							<para>Simply choose a color in the color picker and drag the color from
								the preview field to the left of the dialog onto the
								component.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Customizing the Workspace</title>
				<para>You can customize the modeler by changing window sizes or moving windows to
					different locations.</para>
				<para>For example, suppose you might want to have the miniview in a separate window
					next to the workspace instead of having it hidden behind the process element
					toolbox.</para>
				<para>First, bring the miniview to the fron by clicking at the tab page labelled
					'Miniview'. Then move the cursor over the title bar that displays 'Miniview' and
					start dragging the title bar. You will notice light green rectangle sections and
					circles popping up. In order to dock the miniview as a separate window next to
					another window, drop it at the corresponding rectangle section. Drop it at a
					circle to add the view as a tab page to window beneath the circle. </para>
				<para>For practice, drop the miniview on the rectangular section to the right of the
					workspace. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="Screenshots/Modeler_Customization1.png" scale="70"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>The miniview will be docked to the right of the workspace. You may reduce the
					width of the new miniview window in order to have more space available for the
					workspace window by simply dragging the edge of the window. Now, the editor
					should look like this: </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="Screenshots/Modeler_Customization2.png" scale="70"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>Note that these settings are not permanent. So if you accidentally might have
					messed up yor workspace configuration, simply restart the OpenBP cockpit.
				</para>
			</section>
			<xi:include href="../Common/ModelerKeyboardShortcuts.xml" xpointer="ModelerKeyboardShortcuts-Main"/>
		</section>
	</article>
</book>
